<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Pinpoint</title>
    <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Pinpoint</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 15:37:57 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Town/City Planning</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/town-city-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:54 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/town-city-planning/</guid>
      <description>Our GIS methods allows us to perform:
Land Allocation
Identify land suitability against varying factors for allocating infrastructure whether it is a school, business, education facility, hospitals, housing etc. Land suitability/allocation is the GIS method for you should you need to make informed decisions about site selection.
Network Analysis (Pedestrian and Traffic Movement)
This service gives the client insights in terms of time with a spatial context. Projects that require time as a measure of distance to delivery is for you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interferometry</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/interferometry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/interferometry/</guid>
      <description>Kaikoura Earthquake
Until the early 1990’s, it was recognized that topography and surface deformation could be measured using spaceborne radar interferometry (InSAR). The advantages of this technique are best applied to displacement caused by earthquakes, subsidence, volcano uplift phenomena and glaciers. Spatial and temporal resolutions are so accurate that surface displacement in the vertical and horizontal directions will be captured down to centimeter level accuracy.
Application of this technology in PNG for landslide mapping using this technique would be advantageous in identifying potential high-risk areas relating to human settlement and economic infrastructure such as the highlands highway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Environmental Mapping</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/environmental-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/environmental-mapping/</guid>
      <description>With the current trend in climate change development initiatives and government development goals, we tackle pressing environmental issues with our knowledge and skills in mapping these phenomena through the following services:
Flood Modelling
Take a proactive approach to managing disasters with our flood modeling analysis. With this service, we can model various flooding scenarios to identify populations and infrastructure at risk and target areas for preventative flood embankment development or monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Global Road Connectivity</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/global-road-connectivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/global-road-connectivity/</guid>
      <description>Space syntax is a set of theories and statistical methods that are used to model and analyse movement within cities. This small project applies that theory to model and analyse the street network of Port Moresby in Papua New Guinea* within a 10km radius from the CBD. The analysis was able to predict road segments that would have high volume of traffic indicted by the warm/ or hot colors in the map.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Mapping</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/engineering-mapping/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:14:39 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/engineering-mapping/</guid>
      <description>GIS in the Design and Construction of Projects
Airstrip Surveys
In depth knowledge of rural aerodromes in Papua New Guinea, our service utilizes drone imagery and soil testing that is conducted in compliance with CASAPNG advisory circular 196 for rural airstrips.
Transportation
Knowing if a new road network will ease congestion and improve connectivity in a city is important. Our service will optimize connectivity nodes and produce predictive outputs to test project output and expected results before any construction is made.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airport Inspector</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/airport-inspector/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/airport-inspector/</guid>
      <description>WebGIS
A Web GIS Application for decision support in airstrip allocation and serviceability impact on rural areas in Papua New Guinea. Follow link to access webapp https://niuginitravelor.shinyapps.io/Airport-Inspector/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Airstrip Survey Program</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/airstrip-survey-program/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/airstrip-survey-program/</guid>
      <description>Graphical User Interface
Built using the Tkinter python package for GUI development, the Airstrip Survey program is a user-friendly GUI interface that shows 8 variables which guides the user to input airstrip survey data. It was developed to target technical personnel in the aviation industry in Papua New Guinea.
Airstrip surveyors in the past have been using sheets of printed paper to collect airstrip information and on these survey trips, they are exposed to the natural elements of nature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Carbon Stocks</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/carbon-stocks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/carbon-stocks/</guid>
      <description>Above Ground Biomass
Intimately known as the lungs of the earth, forests sequester carbon dioxide from the atmosphere for stem growth and mass gains thus are a major source of terrestrial carbon. Forests provide many environmental services which are critical such as carbon storage, the hydrological cycle, the atmospheric composition, sediment transport, albedo, global temperatures and wildlife habitat for 80% of the world’s terrestrial biodiversity, however, with average global CO2 concentrations reaching 412.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solar Potential</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/rooftop-solar-potential/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 12:33:46 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/work/rooftop-solar-potential/</guid>
      <description>Ideal Rooftop Solar Potential Location
Determination of Solar potential was performed using ArcGIS model builder which is a visual programming language for building workflows through combining several tools such as slope, aspect, zonal statistics, joins etc. We utilized building footprints and the DSM as model inputs to provide the basis for automation required in scaling up analysis for the project to cover other buildings. We were able to determine the ideal locations of the Pavilion rooftop for installing solar panels that yielded the most solar potential indicated as red grid cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Socio-economic Studies</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/socio-economic-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:34 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/socio-economic-studies/</guid>
      <description>Identify relationships in the socio-economic realm for community well-being and development.
Our service makes it possible to understand human geography and find relationships in occurences of phenomena such as:
Crimes
Assist policing with mapping of crime hotspots in municipalities. The value of this information greatly influences and targets policing activities in crime hotspot areas.
Disease Outbreaks
Containing contagious diseases before it spreads is paramount in safe guarding vulnerable communities. Our knowledge in GIS will assist in the containment of such outbreaks with statistical mapping and modelling predicted trends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GIS Training</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/gis-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 15:15:26 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/services/gis-training/</guid>
      <description>Gain an appreciation for GIS and its applications in realworld scenarios. Solve problems with the power of GIS with real, actionable and defendable decisions based on data.
At Pinpoint, we believe in community involvement and well-being. Imparting our knowledge in GIS will help communities plan and make better informed decisions in their daily lives. Not only that, but inspire entrepreneurship. Having skills in GIS sets you apart as a tech genius, and gives you the software skills to implement in your private projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 09:29:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/about/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 09:29:16 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pinpointltd-png.netlify.app/history/</guid>
      <description>About Heading  The business was founded by Charlie Arua Ikosi, a young geospatial graduate from the University of Canterbury in Christchurch, New Zealand after having returned to Papua New Guinea in March 2022. With low employment rates in the country, Charlie decided to utilize his skills and knowledge in geospatial science by starting the business which would enter the GIS and consulting field by employing himself at Pinpoint.
    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
